Never forget why you are the church.
We're having church.
That's pretty good right there.
Amen and amen.
If you would, please turn your Bibles to Romans chapter 8.
Romans chapter 8.
Listen, I'm going to tell you.
I know people might say, well, my salvation is not based on a feeling.
No, it's based on the assurance that we have through Jesus Christ.
But let me just tell you something.
When you have salvation.
You do feel pretty good.
Amen?
Amen.
But Romans chapter 8.
We're back in it.
We're going to continue right along.
And last week, we looked at the ministry
of prayer.
What do we do when we don't know how
or what to pray?
Well, verse 26 and 27 tells
us exactly what we are to do.
It says this.
Likewise, the Spirit also helpeth our infirmities.
for we know not what we should pray for as we ought, but the
Spirit itself maketh intercession for us with
groanings which cannot be uttered.
And he that searcheth the hearts know it.
That's God.
What is the mind of the Spirit, because he maketh intercession for
the saints according to the will of God?
We pray in the truth that the Holy Spirit helps us intercede,
that is, pleads in our behalf and knows our need.
He does all this according to God's will.
Why?
Because he knows that we are weak and he knows what we need.
But what is the result of the Holy Spirit's interceding?
I mean, think about that.
What is the will of God?
Well, if you look at verse 28,
It says this, and we know that all things work together for good to them that love God.
to them who are called according to his purpose.
As believers, we can know, everyone say no.
That he works together all things for good.
That phrase works together tells us that even
in the trial, the trouble, the hurt, the pain in the valley,
God works those things along with every other
thing together with his will, for our good.
This morning, we dive into one of the most controversial texts in the Bible.
Entire systems have been built upon how
people interpret these 3 verses.
It has been argued for over 1700 years.
It has become even more argued around a 16th and
17th century, and there's also a reassurgence of
the argument in the past few decades.
You have those who have dedicated their lives to the Armenian versus
Calvinist debate, and both sides are fully right
and correct and just in their mind.
So, I have a challenge for you today.
My job this morning is not to change your mind.
Depending on how you view predestination and foreknowledge of
God, an election is how you view scripture as a whole, that is
not likely going to change today.
Am I personally a Calvinist?
No.
Am I personally an Armenian?
Am I a Moanist right there in the middle?
Probably not.
You say, well, what in the world are you?
I am the elect of God.
by the grace of God through faith in God.
That's what I am.
And if you know Jesus, that's what you are as well.
So this morning, let's look at the text.
And listen, I understand you say, well, I want answers.
Well, guess what?
We've had, again, 1700 years of arguing, if
I, I had a pastor friend tell me.
is what he told me.
He said, if you can solve a 1700
year argument, you're either a liar or a heretic.
I was like, Okay, sir.
But either way, we're gonna look at the text and find
out what we know, and this morning I
can guarantee, when we look at what we know, not
what we assume, not what we try to pull and pride and impose,
but what we know.
When we find out what we know, I can guarantee you today, it's good.
Let's read our text.
Look at verses 28.
through 30.
And we know, everyone say no.
Then all things work together for good, so then it love God.
To them who are called according to his purpose.
For whom he did for know, he also did predestinate,
to be conformed to the image of his son, that
he might be the firstborn among many brethren.
Moreover, whom he did predestinate them, he also
called, and whom he called, them he also justified,
and whom he justified, them he also glorified.
If you want to title this morning, it's very simple.
What we know is good.
Father, I thank you, Lord, for this morning.
I thank you just for your clarity.
I thank you, God, that God, you are good.
God, you are faithful.
Lord God, I know that we can sit here and go back and forth, but God,
I just pray that we focus in God on your plan forever.
us
So God, I pray maybe there's someone here.
who maybe they have doubts of whether they are elect, whether they are,
whatever it is, God, I pray today.
They understand that if you want to be elect, get saved.
Call upon the name of the Lord.
So God, we thank you, Lord, and through the preaching the gospel, I pray we see it.
In Jesus' name, we pray.
And everybody said, Amen.
This text is speaking about the plan that God has for his people.
So we're going to establish the flow of the text.
First, we have the will of God in verse 27, right?
Because he maketh intercession for the saints according to the
will of God.
Okay?
The Holy Spirit intercedes according to his will.
But then we see his will established by his purpose, right?
Again, and we know that all things work together for good to
them that are that love God, to them who are called according
to his purpose.
Who is this purposeful?
What is this purpose for?
Well, according to scripture,
It is for those who love God and those who are called.
Now, let's take a moment here to look at this.
What are some truths about loving God.
Here's a good question.
Do people choose to love God?
Now, here's the thing.
Do people choose?
Do they have an option?
Can I love God?
Can I not love God?
How do we love God?
Well, 1st John 419 tells us very clearly, we love
him because he 1st loved us.
Well, we can't love God if he didn't love us.
Well, very true, but we have to set our affections, the
Bible says, on things above.
Colossians 3.2.
Set your affection on things above, not on things
on the earth.
This means that we must intentionally choose to
love Jesus and the things of Jesus more
than anything else.
As a matter of fact, think about it.
On Wednesday night, I was telling the crowd.
I said, listen, I've been struggling just with the priority
of time and this and that, and we say that we have no time to read and have
no time to pray, and we wonder why we're weak Christians.
And so what I started doing is I put my phone, way down
the table, so I couldn't reach it, and I'd put my Bible right
beside my head, so I'd have to go over my Bible to
get my phone, and the Holy Spirit just smack me right upside my face.
Does anyone understand what I'm talking about?
So what I've done is, I've grabbed my Bible, right?
And I've opened the Bible up.
I've turned the lamp on.
I did this right here, 'cause it hurt my eyes, and I would blink,
and I'd do this, and I'd yawn, and then I would dig into God's word.
Here's the thing, why?
I want to love him more than anything else.
So therefore, what you love is what you
put your time towards.
Amen.
So so I want, there was a decision made in
the morning to love Jesus and his word to
put my affection on things above rather
than reach over that and put my affection
on things earthly.
So yes, we love him because he 1st loved us,
but we have to intentionally love him and set our affections on him.
Are y'all with me thus far?
Moreover, the Bible says, we will not obey God if we do not love him.
John 14,21, he that hath my commandments and keepeth
them, he it is that loveth me.
And he that loveth me shall be loved in my father, and I
will love him, and will manifest myself to him.
Listen, you cannot love God and not keep his commandments.
Are you hearing me?
Listen to me back slit in person in the room.
If your neck just got sweaty, it's you.
You cannot love God.
It doesn't matter how much you say it.
Doesn't matter how much you proclaim it.
doesn't matter how much you post it on Instagram or Facebook.
You cannot love God.
and neglect to obey his commandments.
Now here's the thing.
You'll have bad days, you'll have good days, you'll have days where you when
you fall and you and you sin, I understand that.
But your life, my life, as those who love God
and are called according to his purpose, must be defined
by faithful obedience to his word and commandment.
What the church has done if we put an in between here.
Ah, well, you know, life gets tough.
Exactly.
That's why we have to obey his commandments.
Don't obey his commandments and watch your life get tougher.
Y'all with me?
Because let me just tell you something.
When you enter sin into the equation?
your life's gonna get more complicated.
Living in this fallen world, trying to serve Jesus is complicated
enough, let's not overcomplicated.
So we see that loving God is a two way relationship.
He loves us and we, out of his love for us, love him.
It is a response to his love.
As a matter of fact, here's the thing.
You can kind of look at this like this.
I can tell you this.
I loved River and Ridley before they loved me.
You know that?
Before we even plan to have them.
We were praying for them.
And we loved them.
Y'all with me this morning?
I know, listen, we're gonna get into, we're not gonna get into the weeds, but I just
won't want to lose anybody here.
But there's the other part of who verse 28 speaks about.
Yes, those who love God, but also those who are called.
This reveals who Paul is speaking about here.
He is speaking about the born again believer.
No one can be saved without being called by God.
Paul explains this to Timothy in 2 Timothy 1, 6, to 10.
Wherefore I put thee in remembrance that thou stir up the gift
of God, which is in thee by the putting of my hands, for God
hath not given us a spirit of fear, but of power and of love and of a sound mind.
Be not thou, therefore, ashamed of the testimony of our Lord,
nor of me his prisoner.
But be thou partaker of the afflictions of the gospel, according
to the power of God, who hath saved us and
called us with a holy calling, not according to our
works, but according to his own purpose and grace, which
was given us in Christ Jesus before the
world began, but is now made manifest
by the appearing of our Savior, Jesus Christ, who hath abolished
death and hath brought life and immortality to light through the gospel.
Notice that we are saved and called according to
God's own purpose and grace.
that leads us to the next verse.
So we know who we're talking about here.
Those who are born again.
Romans 8, 29 says this, for whom he did for, no.
He also did predestinate to be conformed to the image of his son,
that he might be the firstborn among many brethren.
Now here we see without any debate or doubt, what exactly is
God's good purpose for those who are saved?
His purpose and plan for us, that is the call, the
saved by grace through faith in Jesus, is right lined
out in verse 29 to be conformed to the image of his son.
Why?
That he, Jesus, might be the firstborn among
many brethren.
We see this worked out in the church, according to
Colossians 118, it says this, and he is the head of the
body, the church, who is the beginning, the firstborn
from the dead, that in all things, he might have the
preeminence.
So here's what we do so often.
We make all this foreknowledge and predestination and
purpose and plan.
We make it into an egocentric thing till we make it all about us.
Let me just tell you something.
Predestination is not all about us.
It's about the fact that Jesus reigns supreme
as king of kings and Lord of Lords.
That is the purpose and plan of God.
Now, what about these trigger words, right?
Because I know what y'all thinking.
Oh, get to the words.
Show us the words, preacher.
I'm going to.
We going to have a good time with it too.
I know anyone who has ever asked about election and predestination is
waiting for the explanation of these words found in verse
29, so let's continue to establish what we know.
God has, before we even get to that, God has 3 things that are indisputable.
Remember, we're looking at what we know.
We can't focus on some of the things we don't know, but we're looking at what we know.
Three things that God is.
First off, he is omnipotent.
That means all powerful.
That word omni before that means everything all.
All in all, right?
So omnipotent, all powerful.
You say, where is that?
Jeremiah 3217, for example.
Ah, Lord God, behold, thou hast made the
heaven and the earth by the great power and
stretched out arm.
And there is nothing too hard for thee.
I want you to understand something.
God can do whatever he wants to do whenever he wants to do it.
You say, well, that sounds good.
Now, let me give you a caveat there.
He can do anything and everything within his character and will.
Y'all with me?
He is powerfully bound.
all powerfully bound by his own word.
Now, I had a preacher one time tell me, he
says that, listen, hey, God is bound by his word.
And he said, well, you need to tell me what that means.
He said, well, listen, hey, God can do all things.
He's omnipotent, but he can't lie.
He can't steal, he can't, he can't, he can't be lustful.
He can't do any of these things that are sin because he
is also in his character perfect.
So he's omnipotent.
He's all powerful and he's all powerfully bound by his word.
So not only that, but he is omnipresent.
That means everywhere at all times, in all times.
Psalm 139, 7 through 12, says this, whither shall I go for thy spirit?
Oh, whither shall I flee from thy presence?
If I ascend up in the heaven, thou art there, if I make
my bed in hell, behold, thou art there.
If I take the wings of the morning and dwell in the uttermost parts
of the sea, even there shall thy hand lead me,
and thy right hand shall hold me.
If I say, surely the darkness shall cover me, even
the night shall be light about me, yea, the darkness hideth
not from thee, but the night shineth as the day.
The darkness and the light are both alike to thee.
In other words, what the author is saying is he is present
now and in the afterlife.
You cannot hide from God.
As a matter of fact, we have a story about that, and it's called Jonah.
When I heard of Jonah?
Jonah tried to hide from God on the sea, guess what he did?
He got pushed in the water, and he got swallowed up by a fish.
He got spit up, and he actually, you know what he did?
He did God's will for his life.
He could not hide from God.
Why?
Because he is omnipresent.
You said, then why do we invite God in?
Why are there songs like Holy Spirit,
you are welcome here or God be with
us and show yourself with us today?
Listen, God is omnipresent.
Again, you cannot indispute that.
Well, you cannot dispute that, but also, God,
we want to allow God to be welcome in our life.
He's there.
Listen, he's here right now.
We can't get away from them.
But I want him to be welcomed.
How?
By our obedience and faithfulness to him.
In other words, I don't want to grieve the Holy Spirit.
You ever had someone come over to just greed you?
Right?
They enter the room, you're like, ooh.
Wow.
You don't, if you're, it might be you.
You know what I'm saying?
I don't know.
But think about it.
I mean, it's like, man, we're having a good time, having a good time, and someone enters into
the room, and you're like, whoa, man, it's just everything.
listen, you have to understand something.
To grieve the Holy Spirit.
If you are a believer in Jesus Christ, if you are born again,
you have what the Bible calls the indwelling of the Holy Spirit.
He lives and dwells within you.
This right here is a miracle and mystery that I cannot fully explain.
However, how do you balance that with the fact that you can sin?
Well, you have to understand conviction.
You know, that word conviction means pain.
So when you either, A, don't obey
the Holy Spirit's direction in your life, so you don't do what you know
you should do, or you do what you know you should not do.
It's not the Holy Spirit sinning.
The Holy Spirit is not partaking in that sin with you.
What he is there to do is to remind you of what you've
been taught, to guide you and direct you in the way and the will
of God, to intercede for you through prayer.
And so what happens is as a believer, when you sin, you
grieve the Holy Spirit of living God, and there's a pain that
you can't explain outside of, I got to confess and repent.
Amen.
Listen, if you can sin and feel
like you can get away with it or sin and feel like, man, it doesn't bother me.
People say all the time, well that just doesn't convict me.
Well, it probably should.
She's omnipresent.
But here's the thing.
These 2 attributes of God leave him to be nothing other than the third.
He's omnipotent, he's all powerful.
He's omnipresent, he's everywhere at all times in all times.
By the way, God doesn't look at the world like we do.
You realize that.
He's seeing the beginning and he sees the end right now.
We sit here and think, man, why haven't you returned?
What's going on?
Like, is your plans still in place?
He's thinking, my plan's already done.
You understand what I'm saying?
His promises are yes and amen in Jesus Christ.
But he's also 3 omniscient.
He is all knowing.
Psalm 1475 is as great as our Lord of great power.
His understanding is infinite.
First John 320, for if our heart condemns us, God is greater
than our heart and knoweth all things.
This speaks to God's sovereignty.
Again, he does not look at the world and time as we do.
He is outside the parameters of time, and he sees everything from
just to kind of give us an explanation that fails to really
reach it, but a bird's eye view, right?
But yet he is intimately involved with his people and his purpose for us.
What a mighty God we serve, church.
But this is where it gets interesting.
Look again at Romans 8,29, for whom he did foreknow.
He also did predestinate to be conformed to the image of his son, that
he might be the firstborn among men and brethren.
That word for Noah is the word that means that God has and
had knowledge beforehand, that is connected to the predestination of the believer.
It is the Greek term proganosco.
This is knowledge that is not passive, but rather active.
So, so, so this is a question that comes up when people think
this, because right now, when we're cool with talking about
the sovereignty of God to an extent, and we're
cool to talk about man's free will to an extent.
I believe they are beautifully harmonious with each other.
And that's God's plan for us, but let's think about this.
Okay, so you're telling me that if God selected
some to go to heaven, some to go to hell because exactly what
we're thinking right now, what does that mean?
How does that happen?
Well, that is called double determination.
And so I looked this concept up because it's easy to say, well, I don't like that.
And so I got this quote from gotquestions.org.
They do a really good job of explaining things in a simple way.
And it's what I said.
Doesn't that seem to say that predestination is based upon the foreknowledge of God?
Of course, the answer is, yes, it does teach that predestination is
based on the foreknowledge of God, but God's foreknowledge or
knowing things or events before they exist or happen is
not the only basis for predestination.
We know that his will and his
pleasure are also involved.
God foreknowing and predestining reveals his sovereignty,
but we also learn in the Bible that people are held accountable for their choices.
The real issue is not whether or
not God knows who will believe, but why some believe in others do not.
God's desire is that all be saved and
come to repentance.
You say, well, how do you know that?
Well, 1st Timothy 24 says, who will have all men talking about God?
To be saved and to come unto the knowledge of the truth?
2nd Peter 3, verse 9 says this, the Lord is
not slack concerning his promise, as some men count
slackness, but is long suffering to us, we're not
willing that any should perish, but that all should come to repentance.
Now, some people will say, well, that all just means the elect.
No, they all in the Greek, you know what it means?
All.
Totality.
Oh, fully.
God desires all to
come to repentance.
He offers salvation to everyone.
Titus 211 says, for the grace of God.
that bringing salvation hath appeared to all men.
You know what that Greek word all means?
Oh, yet we know that not everyone will be saved.
For double predetermination to be true.
Hear me.
God would have to go against his own revealed will and desire.
Remember, God is bound by his character.
He cannot change, and he cannot disagree with himself.
Therefore, if his will is for all to be saved.
And if it's grace that brings salvation has appeared to all men, that
means that in this particular text, predestination must be connected to
his purpose rather than simply who gets salvation, who doesn't?
That word appeared in Titus 211 means illuminate.
Now, if you think illumination, and you think light.
There is a one chapter in one book of the Bible,
that you should instantly think about.
And that's the book of John.
So we think of illumination, right?
And John one, 4, and 5 says, in him was life,
and the life was the light of men, and the light shineth in darkness,
and the darkness comprehended it not.
If we continue in verses 6 through 13, it says, there
was a man sent from God whose name was John.
The same came for a witness to bear witness to the light.
We're talking about John the Baptist here.
that all men through him might believe.
He was not that light talking about John the Baptist, but was sent to
bear witness of that light.
That was the true light, which lighteth every man that cometh into the world.
He was in the world and the world was made by him and the world knew him not.
He came unto his own and his own received him not.
But as many as received him, to them, gave you
power to become the sons of God, even to them that believe on his name, which
were born not of blood, nor the flesh of the, nor the will of
the flesh, nor the will of man, but of God.
In other words, but the will of God.
So according to the word of God, he knew that those who would receive him
would be predestined to be conformed to the image of his son.
I appreciate the new American commentary quote on this.
In the present context, predestination is not concerned with election to salvation.
Rather, God has foreordained the believers, be brought into moral
conformity, the lightness of his son.
What is predestined is that we become like Christ.
This establishes the supreme standing of King Jesus.
that he is the firstborn of many brethren.
He then continues the overall description of his purpose in Romans 8.30.
Moreover, whom he did predestinate, them he also called, and
whom he called, them he also justified, and whom he justified, them he also glorified.
Those he predestined, he called, he justified, that is to declare righteous
before God, and this all works to the end result of being glorified.
Now, what is glorification?
First John 32 gives a good description.
Beloved, now are we the sons of God and it does not yet
appear what we shall be, but we know that when
he shall appear, we shall be like him, for
we shall see him as he is.
The glorification is the culmination of our salvation.
It is the final stage that brings us into eternity with Jesus.
It is the taking off of the corruptible to put on the
incorruptible.
It is a taking off of the mortal, to put on the immortality.
It is the removal of the flesh so that we can enjoy perfect fellowship with Jesus.
But if you look at the text, obviously, that has not happened yet.
You ain't got to look in the mirror alone, no, man, I ain't glorified yet.
Amen.
But here's the thing.
Why in the world does he say this then?
In Romans 8.30?
Again, he said, more of whom he did predestinate?
Then he also called, and whom he called, and then he also justified, and whom
he justified, then he also glorified.
What tense is that verse?
It's in past tense.
Here's why.
Because ever since the beginning of time.
The world was even formed.
before the foundations of the world,
there was a divine decree.
Those who had received Jesus, Lord and Savior, will
be glorified.
It is as good as done in the eyes and mind of God because it
was always his purpose and will.
Ephesians one, 4, and 6, according as he hath chosen us in him before
the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and without blame before him
in love, having predestinated us into the adoption of children
by Jesus Christ to himself, according to the good pleasure of his
will, to the praise of the glory of his grace, wherein he hath
made us accepted in the beloved.
Church, we will never truly understand the balance between
God's sovereignty and man's free will.
We will never.
Listen, I guarantee you right now, there are people either listening online,
because I know there's probably a few pastors listening, because I talk to them about this message, and
there's some people right here right now that are listening, that you might be thinking in your mind.
Oh, well, this says this, this, says that, and this, and that, and you're arguing for your side right now.
Listen, hey, is God intimately and intentionally,
is his foreknowledge, intimate, and intentional and active?
Yes.
Do we have to respond in faith?
We will not on this earth close a debate that is 1700 years old.
By the way, if you don't like that, you realize that's the design of God.
You say, what?
You tell me God wants us confused?
No, no, no.
No, we confuse things.
God is not the author of confusion.
You don't think the enemy loves, that we have different camps pointing our fingers at each other?
Well, I believe it in this way, and you believe it in that way, so we can't fellowship.
We can't minister together.
We can't do nothing together, forget you, forget you, all this stuff.
What is that done?
That is, that is, that has divided the church or the living God.
The body has been broken.
And it's all because we really just don't understand everything about God.
You say, well, how is that the design of God?
Just to skip a little bit.
Romans 11,33 through 36 says this, oh, the depth of the riches.
Both of the wisdom and knowledge of God.
Hear this.
How unsearchable are his judgments.
And his ways past finding out for
who hath known the mind of the Lord, or who hath been his counselor,
or who hath 1st given to him, and it shall be recompensed unto him again.
For of him and through him, and to him are all
things to him, to whom be glory forever.
Amen.
My desire today was not to change minds or win
arguments, but rather declare what we know.
So what do we know?
God purposed from the beginning for those who received Jesus to
be like Christ.
He did this through sending his only begotten son, Jesus dying
a cross for our sins and be risen to life 3 days later.
His Holy Spirit, right now, who the preaching the gospel is
drawing the lost to him.
Hear me.
I believe when the gospel is preached, people are drawn.
They may not get up and shout, they may not respond.
Listen, you do realize the gospel is preached the day of Pentecost.
Only 3000 was added.
There's a lot more than 3000, a lot more than 3000 heard
it, but the 3000 responded because they, what do we do now?
You say, well, you can't resist grace.
Well, here's the thing.
We talk about dispensations, and I don't want to get in the weeds with this, but just a few examples.
How about the young rich ruler who rejected Jesus Christ,
God in the flesh, right to his face.
The Bible literally says, and Jesus loved him.
Sell all your stuff and follow me.
That's an invitation.
What did he do?
He left away grieved.
because he had many possessions.
How about when Paul was testifying at court
and Festus said, Paul, you just about persuaded me to be a Christian?
Why would he say that?
If his heart wasn't being pierced.
We have no indication that he ever became a Christian.
All I'm trying to say is this.
What we know, the Holy Spirit, right now, if you're lost,
I believe the Holy Spirit has drawn you to Christ.
Romans 10, 9 through 10, what do we know?
That if thou shalt confess with thy mouth, the Lord Jesus shalt believe in
thy heart that God hath raised them from the dead, thou shalt be saved.
For what the heart man believeth unto righteousness, and what
the mouth confession is made into salvation.
What do we know?
Romans 10, 13, for whose service shall call upon the name of the Lord shall be saved?
And what is the result?
Who he predestines, he calls, who he calls, he justifies, who he justifies.
There is good as glorified eternally with Jesus.
What God starts, he finishes.
So all I can tell you today is what we know.
And it's good.
Now you say, well, why would Paul be encouraging?
us with this scripture.
Like what, you know, why is there so much confusion?
Well, I believe in verse 31, he
goes a little extra step and he says this.
What shall we then say to these things?
Paul literally says this.
Okay, I know that I just dropped a bomb on you.
I mean, listen, remember, this is deep theological study here in Romans.
That's why it's been like 14 years, and we're in chapter 8.
Amen?
This is the 7th message in chapter 8.
And I'm like, we're in the middle.
So, so, Paul, literally, he dropped...
you imagine hearing that for the 1st time?
Could you imagine that letter being read to you
before John Calvin before Arminianism, before all
these different systems of theology happen, it's just, boom, that's who we are?
Paul says this, what shall we say then?
To me, this is very, this could very well
be the most important part of this right here.
What shall we say then?
Look what it says in verse 31.
Look at it with me.
If God be for us.
Who can be against us?
We'll talk more about that next week, but the answer is no
one and nothing.
So today my prayer is to echo D. L. Moody.
Lord, save the elect, and then elect some more.
My mission today is to echo the mindset of Charles Spersion.
If God would have painted a yellow stripe on the backs of the elect.
I would go around lifting shirts.
But since he didn't, I must preach whosoever will, and
when whatsoever believes, I know that he is one of the elect.
But both of those examples of men that
follow God speaking pale in comparison
to the mandate giving by Jesus Christ himself in
Matthew 28, verse 19 through 20, go ye
therefore and teach all nations, baptizing
them in the name of the Father and the Son of the Holy Ghost, teaching them
to observe all things whatsoever I have commanded you.
And lo, I am with you always, even unto the end of the world, amen.
What shall we then say to these things?
If God be for us?
Who can be against us?
Today I have 2 questions.
Are you as good as glorified?
Do you know the strength and the courage and boldness
that gives us to know that the work
that was begun in us is good as finished?
There are religious beliefs
and the nominations that will tell you, well,
you're not saved yet.
You'll know you're saved when you get there.
But then God says that I'm as good as there.
In other words, listen, if we have to continuously
try to work, and anytime someone says that you will be saved,
they will always attach it to what you've done.
And let me just tell you something.
You haven't done enough to go to heaven.
But you've done planning to go to hell.
That's why it's very important for his will and his purpose and his plan.
So are you as good as glorified?
Have you been saved?
You say, preacher, again, how do I become the elect?
I'm confused.
Am I calling am I elected?
Am I predestined?
Does God foreknow me?
Hey, hey, get saved.
You know what I love about this debate?
My job doesn't change.
I'm gonna continue to preach the gospel.
As a matter of fact, your job doesn't change either.
We are to share the good news that Jesus lived,
died, and rose again.
So today, are you as good as glorified?
If not, get saved today.
Two.
Are you living as a good steward of the manifold grace of God?
We ought not wait.
till that day that God already sees and it's already done.
But for us in our mind, since we are in the parameters of time, we are
in the parameters of hours, days, months, years.
That's how we operate.
We don't have time to wait.
We ought to live like him today.
The grace that he has so shown us.
The mercy that he has so shown us, the long
suffering, the kindness, the all the things that
God has shown and given us should result in
a life that is obedient and faithful to him.
So this morning,
There are legitimately 2 people here today.
Two groups of people.
You have the elect and you have the lost.
And that makes you squirm a little bit.
Give your life to Christ.
I have never worried about the term elect.
Why?
Because I am.
Elected.
So this morning, when Hezban eyes closed all over this place.